Richard Hendriks

Programmer

≅ About

☑ r.hendriks@piedpiper.com

(912) 555-4321

piedpiper.com

siliconHBO

♠ SiliconHBO

(o) siliconhbo

X Skills

Expert

Git-Ops/IAC

K8 Docker CI/CD

Observability Git

Frontend

React Pug/SASS

Typescript Node Express

Backend

Python Ruby GRPC

Kafka Protobuf

ETL Pipeline pSql/noSql

Redis TSDBs

Advanced

Project Management

Agile/Kanban Scrum Master

Jira Sheets/Excel

Task Decomposition

Technical Design

UML/C4 DDD EA

TOGAF

Experimenting

Experimenting

Solidity

Substrate (blockchain) Rust

VectorDBs

A■ Languages

Java C++ MIPS

Expert Typescript Advanced Bash/Shell SASS/CSS Experimenting Kotlin Rust Legacy

Summarv

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a lengthlimited conversation!



Experience



Pied Piper | CEO/President

2014-04-13 - Present

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores™ that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Hooli | Software Engineer

2013-01-01 - 2014-04-06

Worked on optimizing the backend algorithms for Hooli

Volunteer

Teacher

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

· Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

Education

Stanford | B.S | Computer Science

2011-06-01 - 2014-01-01

Palo Alto, C

GPA 4.0

Machine Learning

• DB1101 - Basic SQL

• CS2011 - Java Introduction



Digital Compression Pioneer Award | Techcrunch

There is no spoon.

Publications

Hooli

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

66 References

66 It is my pleasure to recommend Richard. That is all.

- Erlich Bachman



Favorite Books

